ARAM MIRZADEH

Centereach, NY 11720 | (631) 509-2726 | aram@mirzadeh.us | www.mirzadeh.us

PROFILE

A goal-orientated software architect and engineer with considerable experience across multiple disciplines of IT. Known for savvy problem solving and delivering results. Excellent communication skills and a deep understanding of bare metal and cloud technologies to help formulate complete solutions where required. Highly proficient in Software Development, Product Life Cycle, Project Management, Agile, DevOps and Programming.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Agile Principles & Methods
- Amazon Web Services
- Architecture
- Cloud Solutions
- Code Review & Mentorship
- DevOps & CI/CD
- Google Compute
- ITIL model/Service Management
- PaaS/SaaS Design
- Programming (Java, Python, Shell)
- Product Life Cycle
- REST / SOAP
- RDBMS
- Solution Delivery
- Technical Project Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Self-Employed Feb 20 – Jun 20

Consultant

- Worked with existing team to migrate legacy application from Java 7 to 11
- Creating plan on migrating from procedural to functional
- Created plan for TDD, proper source control and devop procedures
- Provided guidance on job descriptions and developer roles for future growth of application development team
- Created and implemented a weekly schedule for development, code review and source control procedures
- Assisted in creating a budget and procedures for migration of production environment to cloud, with security and HA considerations

Dimension Data - New York, NY (NTT Ltd.)

Jun 03 - Dec 19

System Architect, Group R&D

3 years 8 years

Lead Application Architect, Group CTO office

2 years

Application Architect, Group Networking & Consulting

3 year

Senior Proactive Engineer, Dimension Data North America, Service & Delivery

- Designed and implemented a custom, top-tier user experience, automated assessment system, SaaS solution, that grew to generate 600 assessments per year on average. The service, annually, generated over \$100M in sales and an \$800M in follow on revenue per year in related services and parts.
- Acted as Technical Product Manager of three global products (Assessment Automation, Innersourcing, Global DevOps), collaborating with departments to collect and maintain requirements, prioritizing and establishing a global road map.
- Managed a team of international full Java, PHP, AngularJS/Javascript developers to create a three-tier application to
 import, analyze, enrich, and automate report generation. The app provided a business intelligence layer with SME
 approved recommendations that reduced manual report generation time and increase business IP.
- As development manager, using agile development, we migrated a monolith assessment application to an API based set of microservice running on a Kubernetes cluster, as a cloud-ready application.
- Managed a complex roadmap of features, functions and onboarding schedule with aggressive delivery schedules working with a large codebase and high standard for quality and systematic testing.
- Worked with Dimension Data Cloud team to compare and contrast systematic differences between offerings of DD Cloud, GCP, and AWS. Assisted in developing HashiCorp Terraform drivers for DD Cloud, for internal use.

- Designed, and implemented a 16TB Data Lake/Warehouse to report stored IP, and assisted in generating annual "Dimension Data Network Barometer Report" used various media/research (ex: Gartner) firms.
- Supervised multiple external contractors in short and long term projects with spec, design, and delivery.
- Implemented a fault-tolerant/HA global secret store with OTP auth, and SSH key CA capabilities with support tools with HashiCorp Vault.
- Proposed and secured resources to implement a company-wide, our "Global DevOps Tools." The toolset consisted of GitLab for code repository and CI/CD pipelines, JFrog Artifactory for artifact and container storage, JFrog Xray for artifact security scanner, SonarSource Sonarqube for code analysis, and HashiCorp Vault for secret management. This project saved \$3M worth of external costs, and consolidated licensing of tools wither another several million dollar savings.
- Led the implementation of a global toolset, with responsibilities of onboarding of groups and projects. With feedback from regions, I formulated and implemented an best practices policies and procedures for DevOps within the international multi-national organization for 30,000 users.
- Installed and managed an artifact storage system within the organization. At the end of 2019, the system stored over 30,000 artifacts and 400GB of managed internal assets, including Maven, NPM, Docker, NuGet using JFrog Artifactory.
- Mentored and help onboard teams from all regions to assist in setting up and using best practices for using the Global DevOps toolset, further reducing our security profile and number of instances needed.
- Administrated SonarSource Sonarqube and JFrog Xray as the global code quality scanner with custom rules to check and report security issues, prevent non-compliance code, dependency license management, improperly static token/passwords, IP address vs. DNS usage.
- Implemented an automated repository registration service (provider agnostic, Self-Hosted repositories, GitLab, GitHub, BitBucket) and project registration as an internally hosted application to catalog and share knowledge of what is available within the company.
- Managed and implemented API connections to ServiceNow ITIL CM for asset tracking of customer devices.
- Engaged internal teams to compile a list of data points to retain in open-source license usage, tracking dependencies, known CVSS issues, deployment frequency, success/failure rate in changes.
- Modeled and led the team to develop, implement, monitor, and generate monthly reports for 20,000+ servers for a multi-national pharmaceutical client with custom health/log monitoring and alerting features.
- Responsible for all KPI, Bi-Annual feedback, interpersonal and budgeting actions for the group.
- Created and maintained requirements, job descriptions and engaged with HR to maintain cohesiveness with Job Framework system. Was primary decision maker for hiring decisions within the team.

Lloyd Staffing - Hauppauge, NY

2002-2003

Consultant for Dimension Data

• Consulted in design, gap analysis, budgeting, and deployment of an automated monitoring platform and agents across multiple operating systems and for a large multi-national client.

Cendant Corporation – Garden City, NY

2000-2002

Technical Infrastructure Manager

- Managed 24x7x365 Tier 1 travel booking interchange system.
- Managed large team to maintain and upkeep in house NOC and data center infrastructure systems for all Cendant companies (Avis, Century 21, Coldwell, Howard Johnsons, RCI)

Cablevision System Corporation - Bethpage, NY

1999-2000

Lead UNIX Administrator

- Launched and supported the implementation for the launch of Optimum Online DOCSIS, iO Digital Television service, digital set-tops in the tri-state area.
- Designed and implemented support tools, servers, storage, and applications for Cablevision technical support for end-users.

Technical Support, Lead

- Led a team of Server and end-user support engineers in all day-to-day tasks.
- Y2K Migration and remediation.

Qosina Corporation - Edgewood, NY

1995-1997

IT Manager

- Led a small team to support business, employees, eBusiness applications, and web stores.
- Participated in defining and implementing ISO9001 certification.

EDUCATION

University of Phoenix, Bachelors Degree, eBusiness

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Apache Software Foundation, Director; emeritus (multiple open source projects) Brookhaven Arts & Humanities Council (photography)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Automation: Ansible, Chef, Vagrant

Build tools: Ant, Gradle, Maven, NPM, make

CI/CD DevOps tool set: GitHub/BitBucket, GitLab, JFrog Artifactory, Jenkins, Sonarsource SounarQube

Cloud Providers: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Compute (GCS), NTT Cloud, OpenStack

Cloud/Virtual Technologies: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Docker, Microsoft Azure, Pivotal Cloud Foundry, ServiceNow, VMWare, vSphere

Database: CouchDB, Couchbase (nosql), Elasticsearch / ELK (nosql), MongoDB (nosql), MySQL, Postgres

Data Visualization: Grafana, Kibana, Neo4J, Tableau

Development Methodologies: Agile, Kanban, Scrum, Waterfall

Frameworks/Dev Technologies: OAUTH2, RESTful, Spring, jOOQ

Languages and Frameworks: Angular JS, Bash/Shell Scripting, C, C#, Java, Javascript/Typescript, PHP,

Python, Ruby, Ruby-on-Rails

Monitoring tool: Cloud watch, Collectd, Grafana, Kibana, Nagios, Splunk

Operating Systems: Linux, MacOS, Windows, Windows Server

Source Control: Git, SVN, CVS

Virtualization: Docker, Kubernetes, Proxmox, VMWare ESX, VMWare Workstation, VirtualBox